dubsmash.com 2016-05-28

# Dubsmash - Privacy Policy

**Dubsmash App & Website Privacy Policy**

Mobile Motion GmbH, Karl-Liebknecht-Str. 5, 10178 Berlin, Germany (“ **we** ”, “ **us** ” “ **our** ” and “ **Mobile Motion** ”) is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. Please read this Privacy Policy to understand how we will collect, process and use (together “ **process** ”) your personal data in conjunction with the terms of use for the Dubsmash service, for which we are the data controller, whether utilised via the Dubsmash mobile app (the “ **App** ”), via the Dubsmash website available at [www.dubsmash.com](https://www.dubsmash.com/) or the Web Uploader Tool available at [upload.dubsmash.com](http://upload.dubsmash.com/) (together the “ **Website** ”, the Website and the App are together the “ **Service** ”). Below, we have indicated which parts of this Privacy Policy are applicable to the App and which parts are relevant for the Website. If you do not agree with the way we process personal data in accordance this Privacy Policy in whole or any part of it, then you should not use the Service. 

**Features and services of Third Parties**

The Service may include and link to features and services (such as social applications like Facebook Messenger, WhatsApp and iMessage) that are provided by a third party. Use of these third party services is at your own choice. If you use these features and services, please understand that the third parties that operate them may collect information from you which will be used in accordance with their own privacy policy and terms of use, which may differ from ours. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies or for any personal data that may be collected through these websites or services. You should always read the privacy policy of any feature or service you access carefully in order to understand the specific privacy and information usage practices. 

**1\. Information we may collect from you and how we use it**

We may process the following personal data for the purpose of providing the Service to you in accordance with our [Terms of Use](https://www.dubsmash.com/terms), 

  1. **Personal Information you provide to us:** We process information that is required for the provision of the Service and entered on the Service by you. For example, when you download the App, set up a profile, or access, upload or download any audio or video files (“ **Content** ”) to or from the Service or interact with other users on the Service or your friends who have not joined the Service yet. Further, when material is accessed on a third party platform or social network (such as Facebook), that third party may provide us with the information based on your settings on that third party platform. 

The categories of personal data collected includes contact information like your name, phone number or email address, account information like your profile picture or video, username and password, date of birth and age, user and device information like your preferences, time zone, app version, dubbed video files, recorded or imported sound files or event and communication data, i.e. details about your interaction with the Service. 

**In relation to the App** , this includes in addition also location data. For the purpose of finding your friends and sharing the Service with them, we also allow you to cross check your email addresses and phone numbers with those of your friends from your mobile device’s address book, however, we do not have access to such information because it is fully anonymized via hashing. 

  2. **Personal Information that we automatically collect:** We automatically collect information about your use of the Service. **In relation to the Website** we collect your IP address. **In relation to the App** we collect information about your usage of the service, for example what buttons you click on, and about the device you use to access the Service, for example, the device's unique device identifier, operating system, device language, device region, device time zone, device keyboards settings, push notification token and mobile network information. We collect this information for purposes of troubleshooting, in particular to improve the Service’s performance and security. 

**2\. Cookies and similar technologies**

We use 'cookies' (on the Website) and similar technologies (in the App). A cookie is a small text file used to store limited information about the user of the device. They help us to identify how our users use the Service and so that we can continuously evolve and improve it. 

**On the Website** we use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”), which uses cookies to analyse how users use the Site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the Site will generally be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. At our request, Google will use this information for the purpose of measuring your activity on our Website, compiling statistical reports on overall website activity for us and providing other services relating to Website activity and internet usage. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however, please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of our Website. In addition, you can prevent the collection of the data generated by the cookie by Google, as well as the processing of this data by Google, by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available from the following link: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de>. <http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/gb> (Google Analytics Terms of Service & Privacy). ****For more information about what cookies are and your rights to control cookies, please visit the third party educational resource[www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). 

**In the App** we use our own technology that allows us to improve the Service’s performance. This technology works by registering certain events in our database. These events may include start and duration of user sessions with the application, clicks on different buttons within the application, as well as user input like search terms. 

We have implemented Social Plugins from social networks so that you can share anything of interest to you with your friends and connections in social networks. Our Website contains social plugins to the external social networking sites such as facebook.com (“Facebook”), youtube.com (“YouTube”) and twitter.com ("Twitter"). Facebook is operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304. YouTube is operated by YouTube LLC, 901 Cherry Avenue, San Bruno, CA 94066, USA. Twitter is operated by Twitter Inc., 795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA. The plug-ins, however, are not active until you click upon them. This means that no information that you visited our Website will be transmitted to Facebook, YouTube and Twitter, unless you interact with one of the plug-ins. Then, with every visit to our Website, which carry these social plug-ins your browser or mobile device will set up a direct connection to the Facebook and Twitter servers. In the process the Facebook and Twitters-servers recognize that you are currently visiting our Website. If you are a member of Facebook and/or YouTube and/or Twitter and you are logged-in while you are visiting our websites, Facebook and/or YouTube and/or Twitter will assign this information to your personal user account. By further interaction with one of the plug-ins, e.g. by clicking the Like Button and/or YouTube Subscribe and/or the Tweet Button this information will be sent via your browser or mobile device directly to Facebook and/or YouTube and/or Twitter where it will be stored on your respective personal user accounts. 

**3\. Sharing your information and International Transfers**

We do not share personal data with third parties except where we have your permission to do so. We may process your personal data through third party service providers which act on our behalf for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. In such cases, we will always implement the legally required safeguards to protect your personal data. If you are located in the European Economic Area (“ **EEA** ”), a transfer to territories that are outside of the EEA may occur where these service providers may be based. Where this is the case, we will use measures to ensure that your personal data is adequately protected in accordance with EU data protection law requirements. 

**4\. Security of Your Information**

We take the security of your personal information seriously and use appropriate technical and organisational measures to protect your personal information against unauthorised or unlawful processing and against accidental loss, destruction or damage. However, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee the security of your data during its transmission to or from the Service. 

**5\. Your Privacy Choices**

If at any time you believe that your personal data stored with us are incorrect or if you would like to access them, you can update them via your user profile. 

**6\. Updates to this Privacy Policy**

We may update this privacy policy from time to time to reflect any changes: (i) in our policies or relevant laws; or (ii) in the functionality of the Service. Any updates will be notified to you. 

**7\. Contact Us**

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy or privacy matters generally, you can email us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or write to us at Mobile Motion GmbH, Karl-Liebknecht-Str. 5, 10178 Berlin, Germany. 

**Last Update: May 2016**
